A Guide to the Papers of the Virginia Council on Human Relations, Charlottesville-Albemarle Chapter 1957-1967
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Virginia Council on Human Relations, Charlottesville-Albemarle Chapter, 1957-1967
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9606
This collection contains about 500 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift to the Library in 1971.
Scope and Content Information
This collection largely consists of the official minutes of the Executive Committee of, and of the Board of Directors of the Virginia Council. Also included are financial statements, as submitted to the Executive Committee or the Board, committee reports, some general correspondence of Board members and other, miscellaneous items such as brochures, reports, etc., and copies of the By Laws in various revisions. The collection provides an excellent source for the study of the VCHR, and is useful for civil rights and related subjects.
Contents List
- Executive Committee Minutes, etc. 1958-1961 (Folder 1)
- Executive Committee Minutes, etc. 1962, 1963 (Folder 2)
- Executive Committee Minutes, etc. 1964-1966 (Folder 3)
- Executive Committee Minutes, etc. 1967 (Folder 4)
- Board Meetings Minutes, etc. 1958-1961 (Folder 5)
- Board Meetings Minutes, etc. 1962 (Folder 6)
- Board Meetings Minutes, etc. 1963 (Folder 7)
- Board Meetings Minutes, etc. 1964, 1965 (Folder 8)
- Board Meetings Minutes, etc. 1966 (Folder 9)
- Board Meetings Minutes, etc. 1967 (Folder 10)
- Financial Reports 1957-1963 (Folder 11)
- Financial Reports 1964-1966 (Folder 12)
- General Correspondence and Memoranda (1956) 1957-1967 (Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous: Brochures; Speeches; Material re: General Meetings; Local Council Material; Virginia Equal Employment Opportunities Committee 1959-1963 (Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous: Brochures; Speeches; Material re: General Meetings; Local Council Material; Virginia Equal Employment Opportunities Committee 1964-1967 & n.d. (Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous: Brochures; Speeches; Material re: General Meetings; Local Council Material; Virginia Equal Employment Opportunities Committee 1966 (Folder 16)
  Conference on People, Religion, and a Changing Virginia (includes letter of Mills E. Godwin, Jr.)
- Miscellaneous: Brochures; Speeches; Material re: General Meetings; Local Council Material; Virginia Equal Employment Opportunities Committee 1955-1966 (Folder 17)
  By-Laws
- Miscellaneous: Brochures; Speeches; Material re: General Meetings; Local Council Material; Virginia Equal Employment Opportunities Committee 1957-1965 (Folder 18)
  VCHR Newsletter and "News from VCHR"
- Miscellaneous: Brochures; Speeches; Material re: General Meetings; Local Council Material; Virginia Equal Employment Opportunities Committee 1963-1964 (Folder 19)
  Richmond-Petersburg CHR - Newsletter
- Miscellaneous: Brochures; Speeches; Material re: General Meetings; Local Council Material; Virginia Equal Employment Opportunities Committee 1965 (Folder 20)
  "Novus Magnus," Va. College CHR - newsletter
- Miscellaneous: Brochures; Speeches; Material re: General Meetings; Local Council Material; Virginia Equal Employment Opportunities Committee 1966 (Folder 21)
  Internal memoranda of VCHR: Personnel policies, etc.